Welcome to this lesson on functions.
مرحباً بك في هذا الدرس عن الدوال.
Previously, we used several of Python's built-in functions.
في درس سابق، استخدمنا عدداً من دوال Python المضمنة.
Here, we will write functions of our own.
هنا، سنكتب دوال خاصة بنا.
Functions are useful chunks of code that allow you to encapsulate a task.
الدوال هي أجزاء مفيدة من الكود تسمح لك بتغليف بمهمة ما.
Encapsulation is a way to carry out a whole series of steps with one simple command.
التغليف هو طريقة لأداء سلسلة من الخطوات بأمر بسيط واحد.
For example, imagine you want to bake a cake.
مثلاً، تخيّل أنك تريد أن تخبز كعكة.
You would need to buy the ingredients,
ستحتاج إلى شراء المكونات،
mix them together in a certain way for specific amounts of time,
ومزجها معاً بطريقة محددة لفترات زمنية معينة،
put it all in the oven, and then let it cool.
ثم تضعها كلها في الفرن، ثم تتركها لتبرد.
In computer programming, functions
في برمجة الحاسوب، الدوال
encapsulate all the steps of a process into one command.
تغلّف جميع الخطوات لعملية ما ضمن أمر واحد.
In this case, we might just have
في هذه الحالة، يمكن أن يكون لدينا
a bake cake function and throw all of these directions into this one function.
دالة "اخبز_كعكة" ووضع جميع تلك التوجيهات ضمن دالة واحدة.
Now any, time you want to bake a cake,
والآن، متى ما أردت أن تخبز كعكة،
we just use this function without worrying about all the specifics.
كل ما علينا فعله هو استخدام هذه الدالة دون القلق بشأن التفاصيل.
Functions are also used to help organize and optimize code. Let's get started.
كما أنه يتم استخدام الدوال للمساعدة على ترتيب وتحسين الكود. فلنبدأ.